<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mechanistic Interpretability on Siriuslala&#39;s Blog!</title>
    <link>https://Siriuslala.github.io/tags/mechanistic-interpretability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mechanistic Interpretability on Siriuslala&#39;s Blog!</description>
    <image>
      <title>Siriuslala&#39;s Blog!</title>
      <url>https://Siriuslala.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://Siriuslala.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.133.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:52:16 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://Siriuslala.github.io/tags/mechanistic-interpretability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Possible Research Areas in Mechanistic Interpretability</title>
      <link>https://Siriuslala.github.io/posts/mech_interp_research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:52:16 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Siriuslala.github.io/posts/mech_interp_research/</guid>
      <description>The Purpose I Write This Blog To get started in mech interp research, we need to have a macro understanding of this area. So I write this blog as a summarization of this field to help you and me choose a research topic.
Circuits Discovery Methods basic activation patching (causal mediation/interchange interventions&amp;hellip;) path patching scaling techinques: attribution patching DAS (distributed alignment search) directional activation patching? &amp;#x1f52d; resources (ROME) Locating and Editing Factual Associations in GPT Attribution patching: Activation patching at industrial scale (ACDC) Towards Automated Circuit Discovery for Mechanistic Interpretability Attribution Patching Outperforms Automated Circuit Discovery AtP*: An efficient and scalable method for localizing llm behaviour to components Causal Scrubbing: a method for rigorously testing interpretability hypotheses new Using SAE Sparse Feature Circuits: Discovering and Editing Interpretable Causal Graphs in Language Models Automatically Identifying Local and Global Circuits with Linear Computation Graphs Contextual Decomposition Mechanistic Interpretation through Contextual Decomposition in Transformers Edge Pruning ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Emotional Features in GPT2-Small</title>
      <link>https://Siriuslala.github.io/posts/happy_feats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 15:51:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Siriuslala.github.io/posts/happy_feats/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#x1f3b6;Code in this post can be found at the jupyter notebook in my &amp;ldquo;saeExploration&amp;rdquo; repo.
Find features that reflect positive emotions To find the features related to a specific emotion, I write five sentences containing the key words for each emotion. For example, for happy emotions I have:
1 2 3 4 5 prompt_happy = [&amp;#34;I&amp;#39;ll be on a vacation tomorrow and I&amp;#39;m so happy.&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;My mombrings home a new puppy and I&amp;#39;m so happy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to Mechanistic Interpretability Research</title>
      <link>https://Siriuslala.github.io/posts/mech_interp_resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:12:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Siriuslala.github.io/posts/mech_interp_resource/</guid>
      <description>The purpose I write this blog Mechanistic Interpretability is a new field in machine learning that aims to reverse engineering complicated model structures to something clear, understandable and hopefully controllable for our humans. The study of this field is still at a young age and facing mountains of challenges. While for beginners (like me), there are lots of terms or ideas which are not so familiar (e.g. superposition, circuits, activation patching, etc).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
